我准备好了
I'm ready.
你确定
You sure? Uh-huh.
好  让我帮你把头盔戴好
Okay, let me just straighten out your helmet there.
谢谢你  爸爸  不  一个爸爸  二个妈妈
Thanks, Daddy. No, no. One daddy, two mommies.
好了  你去吧  没问题
All right, it's all yours. Okay, okay.
加油  加油
There you go, there you go.
这是小班第一次骑脚踏车   我真的是好兴奋
Wow, Ben's first big kid's bike. This is so exciting.
对  我还记得我的第一次
Oh, yeah, I remember mine.
是我六岁的生日  我爸带我到公园去
It was my sixth birthday. My dad took me to the park...
刚坐上脚踏车  它就垮了  没错
...and I got on it and...it bent. Yeah.
我从来就没有属于自己的脚踏车  什么
I never had a bike of my own. What?
我们家很穷
Well, we didn't have a lot of money.
但住在对街的女孩  有一辆最酷的脚踏车
But the girl across the street had the best bike.
是粉红色的  把手挂着五颜六色的流苏
It was pink and it had rainbow-colored tassels hanging off the handle grips...
还有铃铛   一个白色的大篮子
...and-and-and a bell, and this big, white wicker basket...
上面黏着塑胶做的小雏菊
...with those plastic daisies stuck on.
听起来很像是我的第一辆脚踏车
That sounds like my first bike.
我爸把他以前的脚踏车送给了我
My dad gave me his old one.
那个女孩让你骑吗   不
Did the girl ever let you ride it? No.
但她把装脚踏车的纸箱送给了我
But she gave me the box that it came in.
纸箱前面印了脚踏车的图案
It had a picture of the bike on the front.
我可以坐在上面  我继父会拖着我在后院跑
So I would sit on it and my stepdad would drag me around the backyard.
真的太不公平了
That is so unfair.
也不能那么说   我也会拖着他跑
Not really, I got to drag him around too.
老友记  第七季  第9集  糖果皇后
Friends S07E09  The One With All The Candy
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
嘿  你们在做什么
Hey, what are you guys doing?
我在为邻居做糖果
Making holiday candy for the neighbors.
对不起  你说谁
I'm sorry, who?
我要在门上挂一个篮子
I'm gonna hang this basket on the door.
只要邻居一走过去   就可以拿一块糖果
and when the neighbors walk by, they can all take a piece.
但我们不认识我们的邻居   我认识啊
But we don't know the neighbors. I do.
让我想一想   那个留胡子的男人
There's, uh, let's see, the guy with the mustache...
老烟枪婆婆   我看过一些孩子
...smokes-a-lot lady, some kids I've seen...
还有红头发的男人  他不喜欢别人叫他小红
...and the red-haired guy who does not like to be called Rusty.
看吧   这就是我要做糖果的原因
See, this is exactly why I'm making this candy.
这样可以知道他们的名字来认识邻居
We can learn their names and get to know our neighbors.
搬家应该会比较简单一点吧
Wouldn't it be easier if we just moved?
早安
Good morning.
有人心情不错啊   我为什么要心情不好
Ah, somebody's in a good mood. Well, why shouldn't I be?
我有很棒的朋友   有很棒的工作
I have great friends. I have a wonderful job...
而且可以在办公室跟助理鬼混
Where you can make out with your assistant.
少来啊  那也没什么大不了的
Come on, it's not a big deal.
我们整晚没睡  都在想计划
We stayed up all night coming up with a plan...
确保我们的交往不会有问题
...so that us dating will not be a problem.
是吗  你们想出了什么计划
Oh, yeah? What's the plan?
我们  我们不会
We-We are not...
让它
...going to let it...
变成问题吧
...be a problem.
你们花了一整晚   想出那个计划
Wow. It took you all night to come up with that plan?
你知道的  我们还做了别的事
Oh, well, you know, we did other stuff too.
你们两个
Did you two...?
喔  莫尼卡  我不会在第一次约会时就跟男伴上床
Oh, Monica come on, you know I don't sleep with guys on the first date.
麦特威尔  马克林恩   班韦斯  我已经不会了
Matt Wire, Mark Lynn, Ben Wise. Anymore.
秦格  今天我要开会  对吧
Hi, Tag, um, I have a conference call today, is that correct?
没错  4点开会   谢谢你   没事了
Yes, at 4. Okay, thank you, that'll be all.
等一下  等一下
Wait, wait.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
他没发现我们在谈恋爱
That mail guy had no idea there was something going on between us.
我得回去工作了  好吧   工作狂
I'd better get back to my desk. Okay, you hard worker!
我会在你的评估表里提到那一点
I'll remember to put that in your evaluation.
我哪一点   你已经来上班两个月了
My what? You've been here for two months now...
你的上司必须为你的表现做个评估
...and your boss is required to hand in a performance evaluation.
但你知道吗  有一件事  我至今还没有做评估
But you know, there is one thing that I have yet to evaluate.
你是认真的吗  不  我一直都想那么做
Are you serious? No, I've just always wanted to do that.
你可以帮我把东西捡起来吗
Can you help me clean this up?
篮子是空的  天呐  邻居们把糖果都吃掉了
The basket is totally empty. My God, the neighbors ate all the candy.
喔  不然的话就是
Well, either that or, uh...
乔伊
Joey.
什么事
Yeah?
你吃掉给邻居们的糖果了吗   本来我打算要那么做的
Did you eat all the neighbor candy? Uh, well, yeah, that was the plan.
但是我走到篮子边时   发现里面就只剩几块糖果了
But by the time I got to it there was only a couple of pieces left.
整天人潮川流不急   他们喜欢的不得了
Yeah. They've been coming by all day. They love it.
他们喜欢我的糖果
They love my candy?
天啊   我得多做点了   嘿   摩妮卡
Oh, man, I gotta go make more. Hey, Mon.
多做一点千层面  因为有人可能吃了一大块
you might wanna make some more lasagna too. because something might have happened to a huge chunk of it.
罗斯  我的邻居吃光了我的糖果
Ross, the neighbors ate all my candy.
我的邻居偷走我的报纸
Mine stole my newspaper.
这简直就是犯罪潮
It's like a crime wave.
菲比  你有空吗
Pheebs, you, uh, got a second?
当然有  嗯
Sure. Yeah.
从你告诉我  那个脚踏车的故事后
Ever since you, uh, told me that story about that bike...
它一直就在我脑中挥之不去
...I couldn't stop thinking about it.
我是说大家都该有第一辆脚踏车  你知道吗  所以
I mean, everyone should have a first bike, you know? So...
我的天啊   罗斯
Oh, my God, Ross.
你喜欢吗   我爱死它了
You like it? I love it.
是吗   喔  天啊
Yeah? Oh. Oh, God...
我爱你
And I love you. Ah.
不是那一种爱
Not that way.
但这辆脚踏车   让你跟我更亲近了
But the bike got you a lot closer. Oh.
这样  把它拿到楼下去
Well, uh, take it downstairs.
试骑一下
You know, give it a test drive.
好的  我的天啊
Okay. Oh, my God.
我的第一辆脚踏车
My first bike.
谢谢你   这是我收过的最棒的礼物
Thank you for the best present I've ever gotten.
别客气
You're welcome.
钱德都快哭了
Oh, and Chandler's about to cry.
我才没有
Am not.
是谁
Who is that?
别担心  我很勇敢  我很勇敢  我我很勇敢
Don't worry, I'm brave. I am brave. I-I am brave.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
请问你是谁
Can you tell me who is there, please?
我是盖瑞   我住在楼上
My name's Gary. I live upstairs.
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
你知道现在几点了吗   现在是糖果时间
Do you know what time it is? It's candy time.
我室友说它们吃起来   就像是天上掉下来的礼物
My roommate says that they taste like little drops of heaven.
喔  拜托
Oh, please. Heh.
你听到了吗   "天上掉下来的礼物"
Did you hear that? "Little drops of heaven."
凌晨4点
Four a.m.
你能给我一点糖果吗
So can I get some candy?
对不起   我们之中还有人得早起去上班
I am sorry, but some of us have to get up early and go to work.
他不知道我不是 "那个人"
He does not know that I am not "some of us."
对不起  但明天一大早我会做一些糖果
Um, listen, I'm sorry, but I'll put some out first thing in the morning.
那好吧   我待会儿再来拿
Well, okay, I'll swing by later.
你住在这里
You live in this building? Mm-hm.
我应该会记得你
Mm. Seems like I would have remembered you.
晚安   盖瑞
Mm. Night, Gar.
你看了你的评估表吗
So did you read your evaluation yet?
没有  上面写了 "极机密"
No, it was marked "confidential."
我刚刚把它送到人事处了
I just sent it down to Human Resources.
拜托  你是在开玩笑  对吧  我故意写那份评估表来跟你开玩笑
Okay, please, you're kidding, right? I wrote that one as a joke for you.
他们会喜欢这个玩笑吗
A joke they would appreciate?
我想不会
I'm thinking no.
你写了什么   我说你是个接吻高手
What did you say? Um, I said that you were a good kisser...
我喜欢你又小又挺的屁股
...and, uh, that I liked your your tiney-tiny touchie.
不  你不该那么说
No, not my touchie.
还有更糟糕的事
Well, it gets worse.
关于你的主动性   我写
When asked if you take initiative, I wrote:
"他几乎不需要指导  就能解开我的胸罩"
"Yes, he was able to unhook my bra with minimal supervision."
至于你的表现会不会有问题  我写  "天啊  希望不要有"
And under problems with performance, I wrote, "Dear God, I hope not."
然后然后我画了一个微笑的小脸
And then, uh-And then I drew a little smiley face.
还有一张色情小素描
And then a small pornographic sketch.
罗斯  你送菲比脚踏车真的太贴心了
Ross, that is so sweet of you to get Phoebe that bike.
我听到那个故事  差点就哭了
When I heard the story, I almost cried.
你差点哭了
Almost cried, huh?
你听到了吗   钱德  "差点"哭了
Hear that, Chandler? "Almost" cried.
只要有人提到《铁达尼号》  你每次都会哭
Hey, you cry every time somebody talks about Titanic.
他们两个只有彼此
Those two had only each other.
菲比真的很喜欢它吧
Phoebe really likes the bike, huh?
对  我看到她带着它过街
Oh, yeah. I saw her walking it down the street the other day.
车篮子里面还有花   真的很可爱
She had these flowers in the basket. It was so cute.
今天早上我还看到她   带着它在公园里散步
Yeah, I saw her this morning walking it by the park.
等等   她带着脚踏车  两次都是
Wait a minute, she was walking the bike? Both times?
嗨  菲比  嗨
Hey, Pheebs. Oh, hi.
你喜欢脚踏车吗   非常喜欢
Hey, so you enjoying the bike? Oh, uh-huh, so much. Heh.
菲比  你会骑脚踏车吧
Pheebs, you, uh-You do know how to ride a bike, don't you? Heh.
当然会
Of course.
我们能看看你骑脚踏车吗
Can we see you ride it?
好吧
0Kay.
看到了吗
See?
我早就跟你说过了   不要跟助理交往
This is why I told you never get involved with your assistant.
只要是地下情   绝对是纸包不住火的
And there's no such thing as keeping secrets when it comes to having affairs.
你听到了吗   钱德
Did you hear that, Chandler?
纸是包不住火的
No such thing.
发生了什么事   我只是在吃糖果
What happened? I'm just eating candy.
或许没有那么糟糕   他们可能看不懂我的意思
Maybe it's not as bad as I think. Y'know, maybe they didn't take it the way I meant it.
当然   你知道吗   因为"小屁屁"可以指屁股
Absolutely, you know? Because "tushy" can mean both ass...
或者是好员工
...and good worker.
我得把评估表拿回来
Ugh, I just gotta get the thing back.
瑞秋   还记得你提到的素描吗
Rach? That sketch you mentioned?
它跟这素描很像吗
Might it have looked a little something like this?
我的天啊   乔伊
Oh, my God, Joey.
你是怎么了  天啊
What is the matter with you? God.
在我买不起色情杂志前   这点天份还蛮有用的
Boy I tell ya, this little talent came in handy before I could afford porn.
嗨   对不起  我知道现在是休息时间  但我真的需要糖果
Hi, I'm sorry. I know it's after hours, but I really need candy.
对不起  我帮不了你  看到了吗  没规定就是规定
I'm sorry, I can't help you. See? Rules are rules.
拜托  我住在外地的朋友  今天来看我
Please, I have people coming from out of town today.
我跟他们提起你的糖果   开玩笑吧
I told them all about your candy. No kidding,
他们是外地来的   你怎么跟他们说的
Out-of-towners, huh? Heh. What did you tell them?
我告诉他们你的糖果   真的是好吃到无法形容
I told them your candy was absolutely indescribable.
有人说它是 "天上 掉下来的礼物"  但那不重要
Well, some people have been saying it's "little drops of heaven," but whatever.
拜托   你不能帮帮我吗  钱德   我们认识那位女士吗
Please, can't you help me out? Hey, Chandler, do we know that lady?
可能吧  她不是住在你楼下做爱时会大叫的那个女人吗
Maybe. Isn't she the woman who lives below you and has sex really loud?
好吧   我只破例一次
All right, I'll do it just this Once.
但你不能告诉任何人  好  求求你  快给我吧
But you can't tell anybody. Yes, yes, please, just give it to me.
对  就是她
Yeah, that's her.
谢谢你  不可思议
Thank you. Unbelievable.
我不敢相信纸条居然没有用
I can't believe that sign didn't work.
你知道怎么才会有用吗   别再做糖果了
You know what would work? Stop making candy.
但他们喜欢它
But they like it.
你是说他们喜欢你
You mean they like you.
或许吧
Maybe.
那就是你当厨师的原因   你要大家喜欢你
Is that why you became a chef, so that people would like you?
你要跟我谈怎么让别人喜欢你吗   小丑
Heh. You want to talk about getting people to like you, huh, funny man?
记住我教你的一切  你会没事的
Okay, now, just remember everything I taught you and you'll be fine.
好吗  开始吧
Okay? Here we go.
就位  预备
Ready, set--
等一下   这个座垫真的很不舒服
Wait, this seat is really uncomfortable.
不如先换掉再来练习
Maybe before we start we should just get another one.
或许我们该换个飞机座椅  或懒骨头
Perhaps like an airplane seat, or a beanbag chair.
菲比  你不能逃避这件事  你得学会骑脚踏车
Phoebe, you can't get out of this, okay? You have to learn how to ride a bike.
为什么  为什么我非学不可
Why? Why do I have to learn?
以防发生紧急事故  什么样的紧急事故
Well, in case of an emergency. What kind of emergency?
如果有人走过来   拿枪抵着你的头说
Well let there—what if a man comes along and puts a gun to your head and says:
"快骑上脚踏车  不然我会
"You ride this bike or I'll--
我会开枪打你"
I'll shoot you."
我会按铃铛分散他的注意力
Okay. I would ring the bell to distract him...
然后我会用中国飞镖   把那个家伙敲昏
...and then I would knock the gun out of his hand with a Chinese throwing star.
好吧   菲比  快坐上脚踏车
Okay, Phoebe, just get on the bike...
我会扶着你   推你  好吗
...and, hey, I'll hold you up and push you. Okay?
你不会放手
You won't let go?
我不会  你发誓
No. You swear?
我发誓
I swear.
好吧   来吧
Okay. Come on.
好了  要开始了  好吗   好吧
Here we go. All right? All right? All right.
感觉不错吧   好了  试着踩踏板
Feel good? All right, try pedaling.
对了  做的好  对  控制住车子
That's it, you're doing great. Yes, take control.
这就对了  嘿
Yes, yes, yes. Whee! Hey!
喔  不
Oh, no.
你发过誓的
You swore.
我认为你骑得很好了  我真的很震惊
I just thought you were doing so well. I am shocked. Shocked.
大家都是那样子学脚踏车的
It's a legitimate learning technique.
嘿
Hey.
外面有些人在问糖果的事
There's, uh, some people outside asking about candy.
他们得等  好吗  我只有两只手
Well, they're just gonna have to wait, aren't they? I only got two hands.
需要我帮忙吗  不  你不熟悉流程
Need some help? No, you don't know the system.
我不希望任何人破坏我的流程
I don't need nobody messing with the system.
还有  你结婚前一个星期  不会常常看到我
By the way, the week before your wedding, you may not see a lot of me.
嗨  骗子
Oh, hello, liar.
听着  我真的很抱歉  放开了你的脚踏车
Look, I'm really sorry I let go of the bike.
我可能会没命的
I could've been killed, I hope you know.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
但你能再试一次吗
But can we please try it again?
我是说  你只差一点就成功了  菲比
I mean, you were so close, Phoebe.
喔  我很乐意
Well, I would love to...
但脚踏车被偷了  警察找不到嫌犯
...but the bike got stolen and the police have no suspects.
菲比  什么
Phoebe. What?
怎么会这样
What the hell?
好  你知道吗
All right, you know what?
如果你不学骑脚踏车  那么我很抱歉
If you are not going to learn how to ride this bike, then I'm sorry...
我得把它收回去  什么  为什么
...I'm just gonna have to take it back. What? Why?
因为  因为它
Because. Because it's...
它就像你买了这把吉他
It'd be like you having this guitar...
却从来不弹它
...and never playing it.
好吧  这把吉他希望被弹
Okay, this guitar wants to be played.
这辆脚踏车希望被骑
And this bike wants to be ridden.
如果你不骑它
And if you don't ride it...
你就是在扼杀它的灵魂
...you're killing its spirit.
脚踏车
The bike...
快死了
...is dying"
好吧  如果你真的那么在乎不惜撒下漫天大谎  我学就是了
All right. If you care enough to make up that load of crap, okay.
太棒了
Great.
你让脚踏车非常快乐
You're making the bike very happy.
知道啦  罗斯
Okay, Ross.
请不要死掉
Please don't die.
我们得在他们看到评估表前  把它拿回来
Okay, I think we can get the evaluation back before they see it.
所以我们得溜进塞纳的办公室   通常他十点才会到
We have to get into Mr. Zelner's office. Now, he doesn't get in until 10, so he's no problem,
但他的助理贝蒂   一大早就会到办公室吃早餮
But his assistant, Betty, comes in early to eat her breakfast at her desk.
那真的很悲惨   没错  贝蒂有点惨
That's kind of sad. Yeah, well, Betty's kind of sad.
所以我相信我可以用这些巧克力把她诱开
Which is why I believe I can lure her away with these chocolates.
我诱开她后   你就跑进去
Now, while I distract her, you go in the office.
知道了  行动吧
Got it. Let's roll.
嗨   瑞秋  你有空吗
Hello, Rachel. You, uh, got a minute?
当然  塞纳先生  你有事吗   我随时都有空
Yeah, sure, Mr. Zelner. For you? Anything. Minute.
好吧   太棒了
Okay, great.
取消计划  取消计划
Abort the plan. Abort the plan.
事实上  我想跟你们两个谈一谈
Uh, actually, I'd like to speak to both of you.
好的
0Kay.
有什么事需要帮忙吗  塞纳先生  或许你想吃点巧克力
Uh, well can we, can we get you anything, Mr. Zelner? Maybe some chocolates?
不  谢谢你  但我可以把它们送给贝蒂
Um, no, thanks, but I'll give these to Betty.
我看过你对泰格做的评估表
So I read your evaluation of Tag.
或许我该叫他的全名  泰格"小可爱"琼斯
Or, uh, to use his full name, Tag "Sweet Cheeks" Jones?
你们之间有什么吗
Is something going on with you two?
我的天啊   你能想像如果有  会怎么样吗
Oh, my God, can you imagine if there was?
如果是那样的话  会怎样
I mean, what would happen exactly?
那样啊   我一定得写份报告
Well, I'd be forced to file a report.
我得跟法律部门商量
I'd have to consult with the legal department.
你们在公司的未来  可能会有问题
And your future at the company would be in jeopardy.
喔  塞纳先生
Well-Uh, Mr. Zelner...
那份评估表是我写的
...I'm the one who filled in that evaluation.
喔  不  对  对  对
Oh, no-Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我以为这样会很好玩
I thought it would be funny.
你写着你有可爱的小屁屁
You wrote that you have a cute tushy?
对
Yes.
我的幽默感很奇怪
I have a weird sense of humor.
很奇怪地   我以自己的屁股为荣
And I'm kind of strangely proud of my butt.
开这种玩笑太危险了  秦格
It's kind of a risky joke, Tag.
这到底是在画的什么   我看不懂
And what is-what is this drawing? I can't figure out what this is.
它倒过来了  你知道吗  那不重要
You're looking at it upside down-You know what? It doesn't matter.
我不是没有幽默感的人
Hey, it's not like I don't have a sense of humor, huh?
没错  我甚至很喜欢写挑逗性的打油诗
Hell, I even enjoy a naughty limerick every now and then.
但时间跟地点是很重要的
But there's a time and a place, huh?
除非你有写打油诗的灵感
Unless you, uh, have a limerick right now.
没有吗  好吧   你知道我的传真机号码
No? Okay. Well, uh, you've got my fax number.
我不敢相信你会那么做   那太贴心了
I can't believe you did that. That was really sweet.
别担心  你可能会丢掉工作
Ah, don't worry about it. No, you could've lost your job.
你在开玩笑吗  有这么可爱的屁股  我一定能找到工作
Are you kidding me? With a cute butt like this, I'd find work.
谢谢你   你太棒了
Thank you, you're great.
你知道吗   什么
You know what? What?
我感觉棒极了
I feel great.
事实上
In fact...
什么
What?
我只是我花了很多时间才把桌子整理好
It's just-It took me so long to get that desk organized.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这就对了
There it is.
怎么了
What is going on?
我们在等糖果   把糖果拿出来
We're waiting for the candy. Bring out the candy.
对  小姐   快给我们糖果
Yeah, lady, give us candy.
乔伊
Joey.
什么事   兄弟   你在做什么
What's up, buddy? What are you doing?
我在等着拿糖果
Waiting to get candy.
快进来
Get in here.
嘿   你不能在这里抽烟
Hey, and you cannot smoke in here.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
糖果做好了  我得让它冷却15分钟
Okay, guys, the candy is coming. I just need 15 minutes for the chocolate to cool.
好了  大伙们  安静  安静  请闭嘴
All right, everybody, just be quiet. Be quiet. Be quiet. Pipe down.
你们是怎么了
What is the matter with you people?
这个女人在为你们做好事
This woman was trying to do a nice thing for you.
她想做糖果  是为了要认识你们
She was making candy so she could try to get to know all of you...
我敢说你们没有人   能叫出她的名字
...and I'll bet that not one of you can tell me her name.
我没说错吧
Am I right?
她是糖果小姐
Candy Lady?
不  不是 "糖果小姐"
No, not "Candy Lady."
知道她的名字就能拿到糖果吗
Hey, if we know it, can we have candy?
好吧   你们知道吗
All right, you know what?
忘了糖果  你们毁了一切  毁了一切
Forget it. All of you, forget it. You've ruined it.
回家去吧  你们毁了一切
Go home. You've ruined it. You've ruined it.
那是不对的  你们毁了一切  你们毁了这个机会
That's all wrong. You guys ruined everything. You ruined it.
谢谢   别客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
你抽了烟吗
Did you smoke?
不  老烟枪婆婆  把烟直接喷入我的嘴巴里
No, smokes-a-lot lady blew smoke directly into my mouth.
你没事吧
Uh, are you okay?
我没事   但刚刚真的有点可怕
I'm fine now, but it was really scary there for a while.
有人将恐吓纸条   塞到门缝下
I mean, someone slipped a threatening note under the door.
对了  我很抱歉  我受到暴动状态的影响
Oh, yeah. Sorry about that. Mob mentality or whatever. I don't know.
我不敢相信  我办到了  我会骑脚踏车了
I can't believe it. I did it. I rode a bike.
我从来没想过我能这么做   谢谢你  罗斯
I never thought I'd be able to do that. Thank you, Ross.
嘿  别谢我  谢谢你自己
Oh, hey, don't thank me. Thank yourself.
是你面对了自己的恐惧   终于克服了它
You're the one who faced your fears and ultimately overcame them.
别说些陈腔滥调的话  又不是《我的这一班》
Don't be so corny, Ross. It's not an After School Special.